

Arkadiusz Nowak

Email: arkadiusz.nowak89@gmail.com

Phone: +31 622527412 Date of birth: 04-06-1989

Town: Dordrecht

Profile

Operating automatic welding machines and robots.

Experience in creating welding processes in laser beam technology, TIG and MIG-MAG method.

Handling welding processes and developing technology of welding.

Supervision of technology of welding stations.

Personnel management.

Project management.

Basics of C++, Java and JavaScript programming languages.

Basics of RAPID language for ABB robots.

Work experience

07.2019 - 12.2021 [2 y. 6 m.]

KONI B.V., Netherlands

Welding Robot Operator

Welding components for shock absorbers with automatic MIG-MAG welding processes programmed in ABB robot. Manipulating ABB robots in automatic and manual mode. I have ability to go through steps in programmed robot's code, reading and understanding RAPID language. Understanding robot's reactions for software. Changing robot's positions, manipulate welding processes by changing parameters, creating new steps for robots. Reading technical drawings.

Knowing welding processes, effects and behaviours according to experience in the welding sector. Ability to visual welding inspection, keeping good quality and recognizing welding imperfections.

Additionally working with 2-Axis CNC Lathe Machine; operating the CNC machine, reading drawings, taking measurements, creating programs for outside turning in Style Control 2015 Edition software.

04.2018 - 05.2019 [1 y. 2 m.]

AIC S.A., Poland

Leading Specialist In Manufacturing Processes Department

Project Management. Validating new production systems supported by automatic laser beam welding and automatic TIG method. Welding with Kawasaki and ABB robots. Personnel management. I was supervising the work of our technicians, collaborating with robotics engineers and other specialists. I was creating welding processes in new projects. My job also involved monitoring current automatic welding processes and making corrections into if it was necessary.

AIC S.A., Poland

Welding Processes Specialist In Technology Department

Creating and validating welding processes on new workplaces, which were constructed for welding in laser beam technology and TIG method. I was planning these workplaces and collaborating with robotics engineers who were making welding machines. I was responsible for creating new welding processes in welding machines and validating them, writing workplace manuals, and training new production operators. Also I was making small mechanical and electrical works.

10.2014 - 11.2016 [2 y. 2 m.]

AIC S.A., Poland

Laser Welding Machine Operator

Operator responsible for welding in laser beam technology which was supported by Kawasaki and ABB robots. I was preparing heat exchanger's elements by welding their parts together with a laser beam. Materials were made from stainless steel. Sometimes I was an assembler which was making assembly welds to prepare details before laser welding.

Education

10.2011 - 05.2014

University of Gdańsk Bachelor of Geography

Languages

- English
- Polish

Skills

- Microsoft Excel
- Basics of RAPID
- Basics of C++, Java and JavaScript
- C++ builder 6
- Java Eclipse
- Visual Studio Code
- LaserNet
- Category B driving licence